Fear in the Night is a mystery, thriller, horror
film directed by Jimmy Sangster.
It took Peggy Heller a long time to recover from the trauma of a
brutal physical assault, suffered in her youth.
When she married Robert, he provided her with the love and reassurance she craved for and the two
settled down in a pretty house in the grounds of the public school where Robert was a master.
But the headmaster of the school is not what he seems and Peggy is convinced he means to harm her - is her fear a figment of her
tortured imagination or are there forces at work that intend to manipulate her anxieties with fatal consequences?
Molly Carmichael, played by Joan Collins.
Michael Carmichael, played by Peter Cushing.
Peggy Heller, played by Judy Geeson.
Robert Heller, played by Ralph Bates.
The Doctor, played by James Cossins.
Mrs. Beamish, played by Gillian Lind.
Fear in the Night (also known as Dynasty of Fear and Honeymoon of Fear) is a 1972 British psychological horror film directed, produced, and
co-written by Jimmy Sangster, produced by Hammer Film Productions, and starring Judy Geeson, Joan Collins, Peter Cushing, and Ralph Bates.
It focuses on a psychologically fragile woman who, upon relocating to a rural boarding school where her husband
has taken a job, finds herself being tormented by a mysterious figure with a prosthetic arm.
Like many horror films of its era, Fear in the Night has been noted for its usage of female hysteria as a central narrative motif, and was
released as a double bill in the United Kingdom with Straight on Till Morning, another Hammer film featuring similar themes.
In the United States, the film was released as part of
a double bill with Demons of the Mind.
The film explores themes of murder, psychological thriller,
nervous breakdown, newlywed, schoolhouse.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.